Guide to the Richard Pollay. Tobacco industry promotion (TIPS) collection, 1885-2012 and undated RL.11612
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- 4000. U.S. Government Reports, 1954-2003; 7
  - 4003. U.S. Congressional Hearings, 1957-1990; 45
    - Tobacco control and marketing, 1990; 3 folders (Box 61)
    - Tobacco issues, part 1 and 2, 1989-1990 (Box 61)
- 5000. Tobacco Control, 1990-2004; undated; 8
  - 5001. United States, 1995-2001; 46
    - Introduction to Program Evaluation for Comprehensive Tobacco Control Programs, 2001 (Box 62)
    - Legal Resources for Tobacco Control, 2001 (Box 62)
    - Media Campaign Resource Book, v. 1 and 2, 1995-1998; 5 folders (Box 62)
    - National Cancer Policy Board tobacco control strategy, 1998 (Box 62)
    - State Laws on Tobacco Control, 1995 (Box 62)
    - State Tobacco Control Highlights, 1996 (Box 62)
    - Tobacco Control Country Profiles, 2000 (Box 62)
  - 5001.1. California, 1994-2000; 47
    - California Dept. of Health Services Tobacco Education Campaign, 1997 (Box 62)
    - Catalog of Tobacco Education Materials, 1996 (Box 62)
    - Community Coalition Teen Tobacco Awareness Project (TTAP), 1995 (Box 62)
    - Tobacco control in California, 2000 (Box 62)
    - Tobacco Industry Is Coming to Town, and It Wants Your Children!, 1994 (Box 62)
    - Tobacco Use in California: An Evaluation of the Tobacco Control Program 1989-1993, 1994 (Box 62)
    - Youth Smoking Trends in California, 1996 (Box 62)
  - 5002. Canada, 1993-2004; undated; 48
    - Alerte au tabagisme/Tobacco: Sounding the Alarm (in French and English), 1996 (Box 62)
    - B.C. [British Columbia]: Leading the Pack on Tobacco, 1994 (Box 62)
    - Canadian Tobacco Control Research Summit, 2002 (Box 62)
    - Comparison of Smoking Bylaw Surveys, 1995 (Box 62)
    - Directions: The Directional Paper of the National Strategy to Reduce Tobacco Use, 1993 (Box 62)
    - Guide: A Guide for Tracking Progress on the Objectives of the National Strategy to Reduce Tobacco Use in Canada, circa 1994 (Box 62)
    - La lutte contre le tabagisme/Tobacco Control (in French and English), 1995 (Box 62)
    - La science, le tabac et vous!/Science, Tobacco, and You (in English and French versions); booklets and flash cards, 2003 (Box 62)
      DVD (RL11612-OP-016) removed to Audiovisual Materials
    - National Conference on Tobacco or Health, 2002 (Box 62)
    - National Non-Smoking Week resource kit, 1996 (Box 62)
    - Recommendations for a British Columbia Tobacco Control Strategy, 1994; 2 folders (Box 62)
    - Regulating the Marketing of Tobacco Products and Controlling Smoking in Canada (Robert G. Wyckham), undated (Box 62)
    - Regulatory Proposal to Include Warnings in Tobacco Advertisements/Projet de réglementation sur l'insertion de mises en garde dans la publicité sur le tabac (in English and French), 2004 (Box 62)
    - School Smoking Prevention Programs: A National Survey, 1994 (Box 62)
    - Smoking Behaviour of Canadians 1996-1997, 1999 (Box 62)
    - Tobacco control binder 1, 1994-2002 (Box 62)
      Includes Canadian Tobacco Control Research Summit; Minutes pursuant to Standing Order 108(2) a study on plain packaging of tobacco products; Proceedings of examination of Bill C-71, regulating the manufacture, sale, labeling and promotion of tobacco products
    - Tobacco control binder 2, 1999-2002 (Box 62)
      Includes New Directions for Tobacco Control in Canada; memo concerning tobacco related museum items; Progress Report on Tobacco Control; Tobacco Control Research Summit Challenge
    - Tobacco Control Program: Building on Success/Vers une autre réussite (English and French), 2004 (Box 62)
    - Tobacco Control Program: Regulatory Proposal for Reducing Fire Risks from Cigarettes/Proposition réglementaire pour réduire les risques d'incendie posés par la cigarette (English and French), 2002 (Box 62)
    - Vers un programme de recherche coordonné visant à atténuer les problèmes liés au tabagisme/Towards a Coordinated Research Agenda to Reduce Tobacco-Related Problems in Canada (English and French), 2002 (Box 62)
    - We're Making Smoking History/Faisons du tabac une chose du passé (English and French), 1996 (Box 62)
    - Youth Smoking Survey, 1994 (Box 62)
  - 5003. International, 1992-1998; 49
    - Breaking Free: The Fight for Swedish Independence from Tobacco, 1994 (Box 62)
    - Building a Tobacco Blockade (Des Wilson, United Kingdom), 1992 (Box 62)
    - Framework Convention on Tobacco Control (World Health Organization), 1998 (Box 62)
    - Hong Kong Council on Smoking and Health annual report 1992-1993 (English and Chinese) (Box 63)
    - Labelling of Tobacco Products in the European Union/L'Equitage de produits du tabac (english and French), 1993 (Box 63)
    - Mortality from Smoking in Developed Countries 1950-2000, 1994 (Box 63)
    - Nicoteen magazine (U.S.), 1992 (Box 63)
    - Panoscope--Tobacco costs the earth, 1994 (Box 63)
    - Quit Strategic Plan 1992/92 to 1998/99 (Anti-Cancer Council of Victoria, Australia), 1993 (Box 63)
    - Smokebuster Special: Gasp! The Crazy World of Tobacco (United Kingdom), 1993 (Box 63)
    - Taxes on Tobacco Products/La taxation des produits du tabac/Besteuerung der tabakwaren (BASP: European Bureau for Action on Smoking Prevention; in English, French, German), 1992 (Box 63)
    - Tobacco and Health in the European Union, An Overview (BASP, 1994 (Box 63)
    - World Conference on Tobacco and Health (English and French), 1994 (Box 63)
    - World Tobacco Day sample materials, 1995 (Box 63)
    - World Smoking and Health--Herstories, 1994 (Box 63)
    - World Smoking and Health--Tobacco in Court, 1992 (Box 63)
  - 5005. Tobacco Industry Monitoring Project, 1990-2000; 50
    - Correspondence and miscellaneous, 1990-2000 (Box 63)
  - 5006. National Conference on Tobacco Or Health, 2001; 51
    - Printed materials, 2001; 2 folders (Box 63)
  - 5007. Light Cigarettes, 2004; 52
    - The Seduction of Harm Reduction conference, 2004 (Box 63)
      CD-R of Pollay paper "Bullshit and Ruses" (RL11612-OP-017) removed to Audiovisual Materialss
  - 5501. Tobacco Smuggling, 1999; 53
    - RJR-Macdonald smuggling case (Canada), 1999 (Box 63)
  - 5503. Ontario Tobacco Control Conference, 2000-2004; 54
    - Printed materials, 2000-2004 (Box 63)
  - 5504. WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control, 2004; 55
    - Printed materials, 2004 (Box 63)
- 6000. Public Relations, Advocacy, Health Promotion, 1935-2006; undated; 9
  - 6001. Smoker's Rights, 1984-1995; 56
    - Advocacy statements, 1984-1986; undated (Box 63)
    - American Advertising Federation--Freedom to Advertise Coalition, 1995 (Box 63)
    - American Smokers Alliance, 1991-1992 (Box 63)
    - Connecticut Smoker (Philip Morris), 1988-1989 (Box 63)
    - Smoker's Advocate (Philip Morris), 1990-1991 (Box 63)
    - Smoker's Caucus (Philip Morris), 1989-1990; 2 folders (Box 63)
    - Tobacco Advisory Council (U.K.), 1991 (Box 63)
    - Tobacco Institute (U.S.), 1984-1991 (Box 63)
  - 6002. John W. Hill Papers, 1953-2001; undated; 57
    - John W. Hill Papers (photocopies), 1953-1972; 4 folders (Box 63)
    - Miscellaneous, 1988-1993 (Box 63)
    - Pollay paper, 1990 (Box 63)
    - Registers, collection inventories, biographical sketches (State Historical Society of Wisconsin), 1966-2001 (Box 63)
  - 6003. Advocacy Institute, 1987-2000; 58
    - Action Alerts binder 1, 1988-1990 (Box 64)
    - Action Alerts binder 2, 1991-1993 (Box 64)
    - Action Alerts binder 3, 1994-1995 (Box 64)
    - Action Alerts binder 4, 1996 (Box 64)
    - Action Alerts binder 5, 1997-1998 (Box 64)
    - Action Alerts binder 6, 1999-2000 (Box 64)
    - Media Strategies for Smoking Control, 1988 (Box 64)
    - Money is Coming! The Money is Going!, 1998 (Box 64)
    - Movement Rising: A Strategic Analysis of U.S. Tobacco Control Advocacy, 1999 (Box 64)
    - Policy papers, 1998 (Box 64)
    - Smoke Signals (American Cancer Society), 1987 (Box 64)
    - Tobacco industry strategies and tactics, 1996-1997 (Box 64)
  - 6004. Smokefree Air, 1991-1998; 59
    - Printed materials, 1991-1998 (Box 64)
  - 6005. Action on Smoking and Health (ASH), 1995-2001; 60
    - Printed materials, 1995-2001; 2 folders (Box 64)
  - 6006. ASH UK, 1998-2002; 61
    - Forty Fatal Years, 2002 (Box 64)
    - Tobacco Explained, 1998; 2 folders (Box 64)
  - 6007. INFACT, 1994-2003; 62
    - Printed materials, 1994-2003 (Box 64)
  - 6008. Nonsmokers' Rights Association (NSRA)/Smoking and Health Action Foundation (Canada), 1995-2005; 63
    - Contents of binder 1, 1995-1998; 2 folders (Box 64)
    - Contents of binder 2, 2000-2005; 2 folders (Box 64)
  - 6008. NSRA "Tobacco Or Kids", 1999-2005; 64
    - Canada tobacco warnings program, 2000 (Box 64)
    - Influence of tobacco "power wall" advertising on children (point of sale displays), 2005 (Box 64)
      Videocassette (RL11612-VHS-326) and CD-R (RL11612-OP-019) removed to Audiovisual Materials
    - Manipulation: The Story of Imperial Tobacco and Its Cigarettes (Neil Collishaw), 1999 (Box 64)
    - Tobacco industry denormalization, 2004 (Box 64)
    - Tobacco or Kids materials and miscellaneous, 1999-2005 (Box 64)
  - 6009. Investor Responsibility Research Center, 1997-1998; 65
    - Investor's Tobacco Reporter, 1997-1998 (Box 64)
    - The Tobacco Industry, 1998 (Box 64)
  - 6011. Citizens for a Smoke-Free America, 1984-1999; 66
    - American Council on Science and Health--Priorities magazine, 1993-1994 (Box 65)
    - American Council on Science and Health publications, 1984-1995 (Box 65)
    - Gilded Leaf (Patrick Reynolds and Tom Schachtman) press and reviews, 1988-1989 (Box 65)
    - Patrick Reynolds Foundation, 1990 (Box 65)
    - Patrick Reynolds press, 1990-1996; 2 folders (Box 65)
    - www.TobaccoFree.org mailers, 1999 (Box 65)
  - 6012. QUIT (Victorian Smoking and Health Program--Australia), 1988-1995; undated; 67
    - Changes in smoking knowledge, intention and behaviour in Victoria 1983-1993, 1994 (Box 65)
    - Children and Passive Smoking (Anne Charlton), circa 1986 (Box 65)
    - Printed materials, 1988-1995 (Box 65)
    - Quit Evaluation Studies no. 7, 1992-1993, 1995 (Box 65)
    - Quit press packet, undated (Box 65)
    - Strategy on Youth Smoking, 1995 (Box 65)
    - VSHP Operational Plan 1995-1998, 1994 (Box 65)
    - VSHP Strategic Plan 1992/93 to 1998/99, 1994 (Box 65)
  - 6013. STAT (Stop Teenage Addiction to Tobacco), 1991-1992; 68
    - Printed materials, 1991 (Box 65)
    - Speaker's Guide and Slide Collection (Joe Tye), 1991; 3 folders (Box 65)
    - Supplement to Speaker's Guide: RJR's Joe Camel campaign, 1992 (Box 65)
  - 6013.1. STAT Tobacco and Youth Reporter, 1987-1996; 69
    - Issues V.2 No.1 to V.8 No. 2 (incomplete run), 1987-1996; 7 folders (Box OV1)
  - 6014. Tobacco Products Liability Project, 1988-1996; 70
    - Document packet 1, 1988; 2 folders (Box 65)
      Packet of incriminating cigarette industry documents
    - Document packet 2, 1988-1989; 2 folders (Box 65)
      Packet includes: Additional incriminating documents; supplemental Cipollone documents; new incriminating cigarette industry documents from Palmer v. Liggett
    - Document packet 3, 1988-1992; 2 folders (Box 65)
      Packet includes: Cipollone v. Liggett Group et al, opinion of Judge H. Lee Sarokin; Daynard and Morin, The Cipollone Documents: Following the Paper Trail to Tobacco Industry Liability; Pollay, A Scientific Smoke Screen: A Documentary History of Some Public Relations Efforts for and by the Tobacco Industry Research Council (TIRC) 1954-1958; Warner, Tobacco Industry Scientific Advisors: Serving Society or Selling Cigarettes?; Haines v. Liggett Group et al, opinion of Judge H. Lee Sarokin
    - Nicotine Dependence and Cigarette Design: Implications for Research, Treatment, Policy and Litigation, 1996 (Box 65)
    - Stop Cigarette Sales to Kids: A 50 State Legal Manual, 1993 (Box 65)
  - 6015. Surgeon General Reports, 1967-2003; 71
    - Best Practices for Comprehensive Tobacco Control Programs, 1999 (Box 65)
    - Contents of binder or Surgeon General reports, 1967-1994 (Box 65)
    - The National Strategy: Moving Forward, The 2003 Progress Report on Tobacco Control (Box 65)
    - News conference press packet, 1994 (Box 65)
    - Preventing Tobacco Use Among Young People, 1994 (Box 65)
    - Reducing Tobacco Use, 2000; 2 folders (Box 66)
    - Smoking and Health in the Americas, 1992 (Box 66)
    - Tobacco Use Among U.S. Racial/Ethnic Minority Groups, 1998 (Box 66)
    - Women and Smoking, 2001; 2 folders (Box 66)
  - 6016. General Health Promotion, 1935-2000; 72
    - American Medical Association--The War Against Tobacco press packet, 1996 (Box 66)
    - BMJ (British Medical Association) issue on tobacco, 2000 (Box 66)
    - Chronic Disease and Health Issues: Tobacco Topics, 1986-1993 (Box 66)
    - JAMA (Journal of the American Medical Association) issues on tobacco, 1995-1996 (Box 66)
    - Miscellaneous, 1935-1998 (Box 66)
    - Smoking Cessation Programs: An Inventory of Self-Help and Group Programs, 1994 (Box 66)
    - Tobacco Use: An American Crisis, 1993 (Box 66)
    - Trade and Health Issues: Dichotomy Between U.S. Tobacco Export Policy and Antismoking Initiatives, 1990 (Box 66)
  - 6017. Ontario Tobacco Research Unit (OTRU), 1990-2006; 73
    - Conference--Youth and Tobacco, 1996 (Box 66)
    - Current Abstracts on Tobacco V.1 to V.6, 1994-1999 (Box 66)
    - Current Abstracts on Tobacco V.7 to V.8, 2000-2001 (Box 67)
    - Current Abstracts--Index issues, 1994-2000 (Box 67)
    - Current Abstracts--Smoking Cessation and Adolescents (annotated bibliography), 1995 (Box 67)
    - Expanding Tobacco Control Research and Evaluation, 2006 (Box 67)
    - Health Effects of Tobacco Use/Les conséquences du tabagisme pour la santé (English and French), 1995 (Box 67)
    - Literature Review--Adolescent self-esteem and tobacco use, 1997 (Box 67)
    - Literature Review--Are tobacco and alcohol use related to Alzheimer's Disease?, 1995 (Box 67)
    - Literature Review--Cigarette advertising and ethnic groups, 1994 (Box 67)
    - Literature Review--Cigarette and tobacco advertising, 1994-1995; 4 folders (Box 67)
    - Literature Review--Environmental tobacco smoke in public places and workplaces, 1996 (Box 67)
    - Literature Review--Ethnicity and adolescent smoking, 1997 (Box 67)
    - Literature Review--Evaluating the effects of price on the demand for tobacco products, 1997 (Box 67)
    - Literature Review--Evaluation of the print and electronic resources of OTRU, 1996 (Box 67)
    - Literature Review--Gender differences in the predictors of the acquisition of smoking by adolescents, 1996 (Box 67)
    - Literature Review--Predictors of youth cessation, 1995 (Box 67)
    - Literature Review--Psychosocial factors in the initiation to smoking among adolescents, 1997 (Box 67)
    - Literature Review--Review of the methodologies and data sources for estimating the economic costs of substance abuse, 1997 (Box 67)
    - Literature Review--Self-quitters and those who continue to smoke, 1996 (Box 67)
    - Literature Review--Smoking among lesbians, gays and bisexuals, 2001 (Box 67)
    - Literature Review--Smoking cessation programs for adolescents, 1995 (Box 67)
    - Literature Review--Tobacco advertising and children/adolescents, 1994 (Box 67)
    - Literature Review--Today's medical students: knowledge, attitudes and behavior toward smoking and cessation, 1997 (Box 67)
    - Literature Review--Use of incentives to promote smoking cessation, 1995 (Box 67)
    - Research Unit directories, 1996-1999; 3 folders (Box 67)
    - Searching for Tobacco: A Review of Electronic Databases, 1995 (Box 67)
    - Special Report--Actions will speak louder than words: Getting serious about tobacco control in Ontario, 1999 (Box 67)
    - Special Report--Comprehensive tobacco control programs, 2001 (Box 67)
    - Special Report--Directory of public use data on tobacco use in Canada, 1997 (Box 67)
    - Special Report--Environmental tobacco smoke, 1995-2001 (Box 67)
    - Special Report--Evaluating the renewed Ontario tobacco strategy, 2000 (Box 67)
    - Special Report--Monitoring the Ontario tobacco strategy, 1996-2000 (Box 67)
    - Special Report--Searchable database of questionnaire items from population surveys of tobacco use in Canada, 1999 (Box 67)
    - Special Report--Tobacco and women's health, 1996-1999 (Box 67)
    - Study on youth smoking and preventing smoking, 1990-1995 (Box 67)
    - Tobacco Free Times/Tobacco Research News newsletters, 1995-2000 (Box 67)
    - Working Papers 1-62, 1994-2001; 11 folders (Box 68)
  - 6018. Public Citizen, 1998; 74
    - Informational binder, 1998 (Box 68)
  - 6016. Advocacy and Health Articles, 1986-1995; undated; 75
    - Criminal Negligence of the Cigarette Industry and How Its Customers Have Paid With Their Lives, undated (Box 68)
    - Medical/Legal Issues in Cigarette Liability (Norwood S. Wilner), 1995 (Box 68)
    - TPRL abstracts, 1986 (Box 68)
  - 6023. Info-Tabac (English and French), 1999-2004; 76
    - Printed materials, 1999-2004 (Box 68)
  - 6024. British Columbia Ministry of Health, 1998-2000; 77
    - Printed materials, 1998-2000 (Box 68)
      Includes Teen Tobacco Teen project, and Gasp
  - 6026. World No Tobacco Day, 2000; 78
    - Printed materials, 2000; 2 folders (Box 68)
      Includes Forum on Tobacco Industry Documents book
  - 6027. Massachusetts Department of Public Health, 1994-1999; 79
    - Campaign binder, 1994-1999; 2 folders (Box 68)
    - Operation Storefront, 1998 (Box 68)
  - 6028. American Legacy Foundation, 2000-2005; 80
    - Legacy First Look Reports, 2000-2005; 4 folders (Box 68)
  - 6029. Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco, 1999; 81
    - Nicotine and Tobacco Research V.1 supplement 2, 1999 (Box 69)
  - 6031. National Cancer Institute, 1998; undated; 82
    - Cigar slides, undated (Box 69)
    - Cigars: Health Effects and Trends, 1998 (Box 69)
    - National Conference on Tobacco and Health Disparities, 2002; 2 folders (Box 69)
    - Tobacco Research Implementation Plan, 1998 (Box 69)
  - 6032. Campaign for Tobacco-Free Kids, 1996-2001; 83
    - Buying Influence, Selling Death: How Big Tobacco's Campaign Contributions Harm Public Health, 2001 (Box 69)
    - Coalition for Smoking OR Health press packet, 1996 (Box 69)
  - 6033. American Cancer Society, 1995-1998; 84
    - Grassroots campaigns, 1995-1998 (Box 69)
  - 6034. Doctors' Stop Smoking Program, 1998; 85
    - Printed materials, 1998 (Box 69)
  - 6035. Health Canada Protected Advice to Minister, undated; 86
    - Analysis of Options for Tobacco Product Promotional Activity Restrictions, undated (Box 69)
  - 6036. Ministerial Advisory Council on Tobacco Control, 1984-2002; 87
    - Correspondence and miscellaneous, 2000-2001 (Box 69)
    - Findings of the International Expert Panel on Cigarette Descriptors, 2001 (Box 69)
    - Light and Mild Cigarette Advertising: Canadian Examples (Richard Pollay), 2001 (Box 69)
    - Light and Mild Cigarettes: Who Smokes Them? Are They Being Misled? (Mary Jane Ashley et al), circa 2001 (Box 69)
    - Misleading Cigarette Descriptors: Recommendations, 2001 (Box 69)
    - Paper 6: Bob Bexon (project proposals for slim cigarettes, the "ameliorated" cigarette), circa 1984 (Box 69)
    - Putting an End to Deception: Proceedings of the International Expert Panel on Cigarette Descriptors; Report to the Canadian Minister of Health, 2001-2002 (Box 69)
    - Smokers' Attitudes Toward "Light" and "Mild" Cigarettes, 1998 (Box 69)
    - Successful Images and Failed Fact: The Dark Side of Marketing Seemingly Light Cigarettes (Richard Pollay), 2000 (Box 69)
  - 6037. Canadian Cancer Society/International Union Against Cancer, 1993-2001; 88
    - Controlling the Tobacco Epidemic: Selected Evidence in Support of Banning All Tobacco Advertising and Promotion, and Requiring Large, Picture-Based Health Warnings on Tobacco Packages, 2001 (Box 69)
    - Impact of Plain Packaging of Tobacco on Youth Perceptions and Behaviour, 1993 (Box 69)
  - 6038. Centers for Disease Control/World Health Organization, 2001; 89
    - Smoking Media Cessation Campaigns from Around the World, 2001 (Box 69)
  - 6039. Ontario Medical Association, 2002; 90
    - More Smoke and Mirrors: Tobacco Industry-Sponsored Youth Prevention Programs in the Context of Comprehensive Tobacco Control Programs in Canada, 2002 (Box 69)
- 7000. Corporate Documents, 1923-2004; undated; 10
  - 7000. "Deep Flaw" Tobacco Deal, 1997-1998; 91
    - Binder of settlement proposals and analyses, 1997-1998; 3 folders (Box 69)
    - Deep Flaw binder 1, 1997; 2 folders (Box 69)
    - Deep Flaw binder 2, 1997 (Box 69)
  - 7001. Corporate Reports, 1985-2002; 92
    - British American Tobacco--Annual Reports, 1997-2001 (Box 69)
    - British American Tobacco--Celebrating Our First 100 Years, 2002 (Box 69)
    - British American Tobacco--Circulars to shareholders, 1999 (Box 69)
    - British American Tobacco--Proposed acquisition of a share in Imasco, 1999 (Box 69)
    - British American Tobacco--Quarterly and interim reports, 1998-2002 (Box 69)
    - British American Tobacco--Social Report, 2002 (Box 69)
    - Liggett Group--Annual Report, 1989 (Box 70)
    - Liggett Group--Brooke Group stockholders report, 1997-1999 (Box 70)
    - Liggett Group--Vector Group stockholders report, 2000-2001 (Box 70)
    - Loews Corporation--Annual reports, 1997-2001; 3 folders (Box 70)
    - Philip Morris--Annual reports, 1990-2001; 3 folders (Box 70)
    - Philip Morris--Profitable Merchandising in a Changing Marketplace, 1985 (Box 70)
    - R.J. Reynolds/RJR Nabisco--Annual reports, 1996-2001; 3 folders (Box 70)
    - R.J. Reynolds/RJR Nabisco--Messages to stockholders, 1998-1999 (Box 70)
    - Rothmans--Annual reports, 1998-2002; 2 folders (Box 70)
    - Rothmans--Notice of meetings, 1998-2002 (Box 70)
  - 7002. Philip Morris, 1961-2004; undated; 93
    - Altria name change, 2001 (Box 70)
    - Contents of binder "Philip Morris miscellany", 1961-1998 (Box 70)
    - Marlboro oral history and documentation project (Smithsonian), 1986 (Box 70)
    - Leo Burnett articles, 1961; undated (Box 70)
      Includes Communications of an Advertising Man; The Marlboro Story
    - Marlboro story, 2004 (Box 70)
    - Philip Morris and the movies, 1998 (Box 70)
    - Project NewCo (Philip Morris repositioning case study), 1999 (Box 70)
    - Project Rainbow (relating to Tobacco Settlement), 2001 (Box 70)
  - 7003. R.J. Reynolds, 1976-2002; undated; 94
    - Contents of binder--Boston Attack Plan (Micromarketing plan for Boston metropolitan area), 1990 (Box 70)
    - Contents of binder--Marlboro Analysis, 1989-2001 (Box 70)
    - Contents of binder--RJR Documents Premier, 1988-2002 (Box 70)
    - Contents of binder--RJR Miscellany, 1976-2002 (Box 70)
    - Review of the R.J. Reynolds' internal documents produced in Mangini v. R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Co., Civil No. 939359--The case that rid California and the American Landscape of "Joe Camel" (Patrick Coughlan and Frank Janacek), undated (Box 70)
  - 7004. Brown & Williamson, 1959-1984; 95
    - Contents of binder--Rosser Reeves Papers, 1959-1984 (Box 70)
  - 7005. Tobacco Lawyers' Perspective, 1998; 96
    - Contents of binder--Jones, Day documents, 1998; 2 folders (Box 71)
  - 7007. Cigarette Advertising Code, 1960s-1990; 97
    - Contents of binder--Cigarette advertising codes of ethics, 1960s-1990 (Box 71)
  - 7008. Smokescreen Documents, 1923-2000; 98
    - Contents of binder--A Scientific Smoke Screen, 1953-1958; 2 folders (Box 71)
    - Contents of binder--Smoke Screen Documents (Addenda), 1960-1999 (Box 71)
    - Contents of binder--Smoke Screen Documents (Addenda V16a), 1958-2000; 2 folders (Box 71)
    - Contents of binder--Smoke Screen Documents (Addenda V16b), 1953-1998 (Box 71)